

Estefania Escarria Garcia

INDUSTRIAL ENGINEER SOFTWARE DEVELOPER STUDENT

I have more than 10 years experience in the manufacturing area as an Industrial Engineer and I am looking for an opportunity in the TI world as a Backend Developer.

I am a person with the skills to work in a team, take on challenges and face difficulties.

PERSONAL INFO



estefy0114@gmail.com



Cel: (57) 310 8499764



www.linkedin.com/in/estefani a-escarria-garcia



Cali - Colombia

TECH SKILLS

Knowledge in:

- Java
- Spring Boot
- HTML/CSS
- Javascript
- React
- Node js
- Git/Github
- MySQL
- Manual Testing/Postman/Selenium
- JUnit
- Agile Methodologies

PROJECTS

Dental Clinic

Reservation system that allows to schedule appointments between patients and dentists. Manage the data of dentists, patients, shifts and it also has Secure Login System.

- Technologies: Java, SpringBoot, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Manual Testing
- URL: https://portfolio-react-eescarria.vercel.app/

Web App - Regarding to Health

Web application linked to the topic of health. It integrates different routes, contact forms, status themes, and others. All this consuming data from an API.

- Technologies: React, Javascript, CSS3
- URL: https://portfolio-react-eescarria.vercel.app/

EDUCATION

Certified Tech Developer

Digital House, Julio 2022 - Julio 2023 (Full Time)

- Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, Node.js, Java, SpringBoot, MySQL, Git, Github, Manual Testing, Postman, Selenium.
- DevOps: AWS, CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible, Docker, Pipelines
- Agile Methodologies: Scrum, Design Thinking, Kanban-Trello, Effective communication, UX/UI.

LANGUAGES

• Spanish : Native

• English : Intermediate

• Portuguese: Basic

SOFT SKILLS

Assertive communication

Teamwork

Responsible

Organized

Methodical

Time management

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Negotiation with Suppliers and Customers Supply Chain Management

COURSES

- Professional Course of Git and GitHub Platzi, 2022.
- Course of Java SE Object-oriented programming
 Platzi, 2022.

Power Up: Bootcamp Java

Pragma - June 2023

Logistic Specialist

University of Valle, 2016

Industrial Engineer

Icesi University, 2011

WORK EXPERIENCE

Response Planner

Unilever, May 2021 - March 2022

It was responsible for the planning of the supply of the Foods category and it was the point of contact for the Capgemini planning team (third party in charge of the operational functions of the area). As a team, they had to ensure that the plans are implemented and the Working Capital and service level indicators are met . This role plays an important role in crisis resolution regarding the finished product or materials, being fundamental support for the third party.

MRP Specialist

Unilever, June 2019 - April 2021

It was responsible for the purchasing strategy of raw materials and packaging material for the plant, aligned with the established stock policies that support the finished product supply plan, in accordance with the business needs. It was also important the participation, generation and execution of projects to improve Stocks and costs.

Supply Planner

Unilever, December 2018 - May 2019

The main responsability was to assure the supply of finished product for one of the categories of the Foods plant, ensuring the level of service and controlling stock levels. It was also important the support for innovation projects to guarantee their execution at the plant and availability for sale on the scheduled dates. This role had to supervise and support the work of the MRP, who must guarantee the availability of materials in the plant for the execution of production programs.